Junior García

Full-Stack Web Developer

jrgarciadev.com github.com/jrgarciadev +541122559178 jrgarciadev@gmail.com hashnode.com/@jrgarciadev

Software Developer, specializing in building exceptional websites and mobile applications with 4 years involved in the whole software development life cycle providing IT solutions for private and public organizations using React.js, React Native, Next.js, Vue.js and Laravel. I like creating and contributing to open-source projects as well as blogging.

Relevant Experience

Full-Stack Developer @ Ecomerciar

April 2019 - Present | Buenos Aires, AR

- Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, producers, clients, and stakeholders on a daily basis.
- Write modern, performant, and robust code for a diverse array of client and internal projects.
- Work with a variety of different languages, frameworks, and content management systems such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native, Vue, Laravel, Node.js, Strapi, etc.
- Developed company website and loading time improvement by 40% also improve user experience.
- Mentored current junior software engineers on software engineering best practices.
- Clients included Mercado Libre, Tienda Nube, Glovo, Chazki, Renault, and more.
- Developed Android application using Java and Kotlin to process payments and sell from a Ingenico Axium D7 tablet in Argentina used by more than 5k merchants.
- Reduce by 30% the administrative operational costs related to packaging shipments by Tienda Nube sellers in Argentina by creating a plugin in Symfony and React.js that allows sellers to integrate Glovo to their stores and thus save costs and deliver packages in less than 1 hour.

Java Software Developer @ Intelix Synergy

July 2017 - April 2019 | Valencia, VE

- Applied clean code practices and design patterns to develop a maintainable and scalable code for a in-house Cash Register Application
- Created new code and improved existing flow using SOLID design principles.
- Developed a module for client search and signup, using Java Swing components
- Worked closely with QA and management team to develop, document, and manage the Cash Register version 2 for Salvador country using MySQL, Java 8, and JPA
- □ Interfaced with clients on a weekly basis, providing technological expertise and knowledge
- Developed a JavaFX desktop application to manage stores setups saving 60% of spent time on manual configuration
- Contributed to improve code coverage by 50% by designing unit and integration tests.

Skills

Programming Languages

Strong: JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS/Sass, GraphQL, PHP, Java.

Experienced: Kotlin, Less.

Libraries & Frameworks

Strong: React, React Native, Android, Expo, Vue, Next.js, Node.js, Apollo, Express, Laravel.

Experienced: Symfony, Nuxt.js, Ionic.

Databases

Strong: MongoDB, MySQL, SQLite,

Room.

Experienced: PostgresQL, DB2

Tools & Platforms

Git, Android Studio, Webpack, Vercel, Heroku, Strapi, Docker, AWS, Firebase.

Projects

CargoMe

Mobile app built with React Native, to connect truck drivers with companies to pickup cargo and deliver it according to their location.

Nimble

Mobile app and administration panel built with React Native and Laravel to purchase in restaurants from a mobile phone without getting up from the chair or calling a waiter.

Education

Electrical Engineering, Universidad de Carabobo VE (2013 – 2018) - 7th semester approved.

Certifications

Smart Checkout Integration - Mercado Libre

App development career with React Native - *Platzi*

Backend development career with Php - Platzi

Interests

Swimming, traveling, blogging, reading.